本期视频由Brilliant赞助，字幕由给虫翻译
This video was made possible by Brilliant.
前往下方链接，前200人注册可获得20%优惠
Learn intuitively with Brilliant for 20% off by being one of the first 200 to sign up at brilliant.org/Wendover.
抬头，你能看到近5000个卫星正在环绕地球
If you look up, there are 4,708 satellites that came from earth currently orbiting our planet.
单单从视野里能看到的天空中也随时有上百颗卫星飞过
Just in the portion of the sky you can see, hundreds of satellites are passing overhead at any given time.
你可能看不到它们，但它们让全球定位成为现实
You often can’t see them, but they’re there making GPS work,
它们为地球拍照、提供通信、甚至为政府提供监视服务
taking images of earth, providing communications, even spying for governments.
这些卫星可以说是人类制造过的最昂贵的单件物体了
These satellites are some of the most expensive single objects that can be made.
平均算下来，哈勃上挖一块乒乓球大的部分就值1500美元
If you took at tennis ball sized chunk of the Hubble Space Telescope, it would be worth over $1,500.
现代的满配置商业卫星基本都值数亿美元
Modern full-scale, commercial grade satellites cost in the hundreds of millions of dollars.
它们极其复杂，需要几年的时间去制造
They’re just incredibly complex objects that require years to construct.
你头顶飞过的卫星有很多来自于加州帕罗奥图的SSL总部
Many of the satellites flying over you right now, though, started their life here at SSL in Palo Alto, California.
SSL是Maxar技术公司下的商业公司，主营卫星和航天器制造业务
SSL is a commercial company owned by Maxar Technologies specializing in satellite and spacecraft construction.
他们制造的航天器已经有很多入轨并为从电视转播到政府部门服务了
They’ve built spacecraft that are current in orbit for everyone from DirecTV to national governments.
如果你看过卫星电视、听过卫星广播、或者在飞机上连过WiFi
If you’ve ever watched satellite TV, listened to satellite radio, or used satellite internet on a plane,
那你就很有可能直接享受过他们在这家工厂建造的卫星的服务了
there’s a decent chance you’ve directly used one of the satellites they built here in their factory.
但假如你想买一颗SSL的卫星，你该怎样做呢？
But let’s say you want to buy a satellite from SSL, what do you do?
“你要做的第一件事是给我们打电话
"Well the first thing you do is you pick up the phone and call us.
其次是看看你卡里还剩多少钱，因为卫星是很贵的
But the next thing you should do is check your bank account to make sure you have enough money to buy a satellite.
一颗卫星，基于其用途与其所在轨道
Satellites, depending on what kind it is and where it’s going
价值从上千万美元到几亿美元不等”
can cost tens of millions of dollars up to several hundred million dollars."
当客户给SSL打第一通电话之后
Once a customer makes that first phone call to SSL,
SSL公司会和客户反复讨价还价
there will then be an ongoing back and forth between them and the customer.
简言之就是客户告诉SSL卫星需求有哪些
Essentially, the customer will tell SSL what they want their satellite to do
SSL会以此报价
and SSL will come back to them with a price.
最终谈妥了就签合同
Eventually, if all goes well, they’ll sign a contract.
这就是SSL和TeleSat公司几年前发生的事情
That’s exactly what happened a few years ago between SSL and Telesat
TeleSat是一家总部在加拿大的卫星公司，运营着很多颗卫星
a global satellite company headquartered in Canada that owns and operates a fleet of satellites.
他们的卫星用于广播信号，可能是电视、广播、或者网络信号
Their satellites are used to broadcast signals, whether it be TV, Radio, or Internet,
并提供给其客户——卫星电视、卫星广播、网络供应商
for their customers—satellite TV, radio, and internet providers.
这个例子里，TeleSat需要一颗卫星为繁忙的北大西洋区提供额外容量
In this case, Telesat needed a satellite to provide additional capacity over the busy North Atlantic region
所以他们找SSL签订了合同造新卫星——Telstar 19V
and so they came and signed a contract with SSL to build their new satellite—Telstar 19 VANTAGE.
合同签完不久，卫星设计就开始了
Soon after contracts were signed, work began on designing the satellite.
这个过程中，设计师会把以前项目中通用的部分拿出来
In that process the designers usually pull designs for some more generic aspects from previous projects
套进当前的项目中去
and then modify them to suit the particular job.
整个设计过程时间跨度和卫星的复杂程度有关
The length of that process can vary widely based off how complex the satellite is,
但设计一旦完成，他们就会马上开始零件采购
but throughout the process, as soon as they’ve locked a design in, they’ll begin ordering parts.
SSL会自制约一半的零件，并采购另一半的零件
SSL builds about half their components themselves and orders the other half from other companies.
自制还是采购的决定取决于具体表现如何
The decision on whether to order or build in-house usually comes down to performance.
“有某些零件要看具体需求
"There are certain components where, depending on what the requirements are,
有些零件我们造的性能比供应商的好，有些则反过来”
we build higher performance components than suppliers, some of them our suppliers build better components than we do.”
SSL多年的经验让他们知道哪些是他们擅长的，哪些是供应商擅长的
Over the years SSL has looked at what it’s good at and what other suppliers are good at
并以此来决定采购哪些零件
and made the decision on what to order based off that.
比如，SSL制造的零件之一是卫星的天线反射面
For example, one of the components that SSL builds are the antenna reflectors.
其作用是把信号指向回地球
These are what actually direct signals down to earth
每一块都是基于卫星覆盖区域定制的
and each of them is custom designed for the region that the satellite will cover.
“比如这个是用于Telstar 18V的
“So this is, for example, for Telstar 18 Vantage,
图中能看到这些反射面会从卫星侧面展开
you can see here that these are these reflectors that would be sticking out on the sides
它的作用就是把信号传回地球，另外你能看到表面很多白点
and it’s used for sending signals back to earth and all those little dots you see on there
它的作用是以此借助摄影测量法保证其表面是符合设计要求的
are for photogrammetry so they’re used to make sure that the surface is actually exactly as was designed
我们有很多相机给这些白点拍照，从而确定该反射面符合设计”
so we have these cameras that take pictures of these and all the dots to make sure that it was build according to the design.”
这些反射面最终会装上Telstar 18V——Telstar 19V的姊妹星
The satellite these antenna reflectors eventually went on, Telstar 18 Vantage, the sister satellite of Telstar 19 Vantage,
实际发射时间为2018年9月10日
在2018年8月底发射，并在不久后为亚洲、大洋洲提供数据服务
will launch in late August 2018 and soon after will go into service providing data services over Asia and Oceania
所以天线反射面的表面会仔细设计
so the antenna reflector was carefully crafted to provide signal over
来精准覆盖人口密集区、繁忙航线、海运走廊
populated areas and busy flight and maritime corridors
并不会把资源浪费在已有覆盖区域
while not wasting resources on providing service to areas the company already has coverage for
或者低需求区域，比如澳大利亚以南
or that would have little demand such as to the south of Australia.
采购完成9到15个月后
About 9 to 15 months after ordering,
主要零件进场，开始组装过程
the majority of the ordered components will start rolling through the door and then the bulk of the assembly process begins.
细节部分太复杂，简言之是分工合作安装各个大部分
This process is too complex to go into detail on, but essentially they’ll first build the major elements separately.
一组人组装推进系统和卫星主体结构
One group will assemble the propulsion system and framework of the satellite
一组人负责有效载荷
while another will assemble the payload,
即卫星真正携带的东西，有时候是高级相机有时候是通信系统
what the satellite is actually built to carry whether that be an advanced camera or a communications system,
还有一组人负责组装超轻、超高效的，为卫星提供电力的太阳帆板
while yet another group will assemble the super-light and efficient solar panels that will power the satellite when in orbit.
这些大的部分的安装还要花费几个月
The assembly of the different major components will take a few more months
把它们组装到一起又要花几个月
and then they’ll start to compile those different major components together over a period of a few more months.
每个零件在安装时和安装之前都要单独测试
Each component is tested independently before and while being installed on the satellite,
而它们都组装到一起后，还要让卫星整体进行大量超级严格的测试
but once they’re all pieced together there begins an incredibly rigorous phase of testing the satellite as a whole.
客户选择SSL这样值得信任的制造商
When buying a satellite from a trusted manufacturer like SSL,
主要花钱买的就是可靠性，所以任何测试都不能糊弄
the customer is buying reliability so there can be no compromise on testing.
他们必须保证卫星能安然度过发射并在太空正常工作
They need to be sure that the satellite will actually survive launch and work in space
而证明的方法就是模拟发射和太空的环境
and the best way to do that is to just simulate launch and space.
损害卫星的因素主要有三——震动、温度、噪声
There are three major factors that could harm a satellite—vibration, temperature, and sound.
震动来自发射的火箭，所以要测试卫星能忍受发射的震动
The vibration comes as a satellite launches in a rocket so they test that their satellites can survive launch.
“当你把卫星放到火箭顶端整流罩内（并发射）
“When you put one of these satellites on top of a rocket in the payload faring
卫星会承受xyz轴三个方向的大量震动
they experience a lot of vibration loads in the x, y, and z
我们要在振动台上进行模拟
so we’re able to simulate those with this vibration table.
它有一个可以向xyz三个方向震动的底座
It has a baseplate there and you can shake it in this direction, in this direction, or in this direction
它会向所有不同方向震动以模拟真实环境，从而保证其仍可正常工作”
so it does in all different directions to simulate the environment and make sure that it’s all operating.”
振动台上的卫星就是Telstar 19V
The satellite on the table in testing here is Telstar 19 Vantage itself.
这只是众多测试之一——射前摇一摇，看看卫星反映如何
This here is just one of many tests where they literally just shake the satellite and see how it responds.
持续时间只有60到90秒
They only last about 60-90 seconds each because
因为这就是卫星在发射中飞出大气前会承受的震动时间
that’s how long the satellite will experience vibration during launch until the rocket reaches the upper atmosphere.
他们还会测试卫星能承受太空的真空和温度
They’ll also test to be sure that their satellites can survive the vacuum and temperatures of space.
“你能看到上面那个蓝色锅盖一样的东西
“So, what you see up there, this big blue pumpkin looking thing like Cinderella’s carriage,
那就是我们的热真空室，我们喜欢叫它蓝色南瓜
that one is called our thermal vacuum chamber, we like to call it the blue pumpkin,
我们用它来模拟太空的热真空环境
and what we use it for is to simulate the thermal vacuum of space
1托(Torr)=1毫米汞柱
它能把气压降低到太空程度的10的-5次方托
so we’ll go down to the vacuum levels of space, you know 10^-5 Torr
然后我们会把卫星上不同部分的载荷开启
and we will turn on the payload on different parts of the satellite
来保证其在太空中时每个部分都会正常工作
to make sure that everything’s functioning properly when you put it in space
另外，当卫星进入真空环境
and in addition to that, once it’s under vacuum,
我们还有这些发热板来模拟冷热环境
we have these thermal panels in there to simulate the hot and cold environment.
当你面对太阳，卫星表面就会变热，我们就要给卫星模拟高温环境
So like, when you’re facing the sun and the satellite gets really hot, we bring those temperature to bear.
而卫星到了地球阴影下，我们就要给它模拟低温环境
And then we make it really cold when it’s facing away from earth in an eclipse type situation
并保证每个部分都能正常运行”
and make sure everything’s functioning properly.”
最后，发射很吵，噪声巨大的能量可以给卫星带来损害
Lastly, launch is very loud to the point that the acoustic energy could actually damage a satellite
所以他们要模拟发射的噪声环境来保证卫星不会受损
so they make sure it doesn’t by simulating the launch environment
方法就是用扬声器对着卫星轰
through bombarding the satellite with acoustic energy with speakers.
在SSL彻底给卫星打上合格标签之前还有无数测试要进行
There are a myriad of other tests performed before the satellite is given SSL’s stamp of approval,
但当它准备好后，卫星还要去发射场
but once it’s ready, the satellite does, of course, need to get to the launch site.
客户会选择找谁发射，可能是太空叉、ULA、阿里安航天或者其他的
The customer decides which launch provider to use whether it be SpaceX, United Launch Alliance, Arianespace, or another
所以卫星可能只要运到开车四小时就能到的范登堡空军基地
so the satellite might only need to go as far as Vandenberg Air Force base a four hour drive away
或者要去地球另一边的哈萨克斯坦拜卡努尔发射场
or as far as Baikonur Cosmodrome in Kazakstan.
发射场的选择也要看卫星最后要去什么轨道
The launch site is also partially decided based off what sort of orbit the satellite is going into.
如果要去南北走向的极地轨道，那它就要向南或向北发射
If a satellite is going to orbit in a north-south direction over the poles they want to launch in that direction
所以发射场就需要北面或者南面有海，这是为了安全着想
so they want to launch from a site with open water to the north or south, both for safety
按照火箭的设计，分离后的火箭可以直接落回大海
and, for some rocket designs, so stages of rockets can fall into the ocean throughout the launch process.
比如太空叉，在加州的范登堡空军基地就有发射场
SpaceX, for example, therefore uses Vandenberg Air Force Base in California
对于极地轨道任务，他们可以向南发射把一级火箭扔进太平洋
for their polar orbit launches as it has the Pacific Ocean directly south.
对于同步轨道，卫星会自西向东与地球自转同步
For geosynchronous orbits where satellites travel from west to east at the same rate as earth rotates
所以也要向东面发射
they want to launch in the same direction as the satellite will orbit.
因此范登堡就不能用了，因为它的东边是陆地
For that reason they can’t launch from Vandenberg as it has land to the east
所以太空叉会用佛州卡角的发射场，向西发射到大西洋上
so SpaceX uses the launch pads on Cape Canaveral, Florida as they have the Atlantic Ocean to the east.
Telstar 19V要进入同步轨道来提供服务区域的不间断数据服务
In the the case of Telstar 19 Vantage, it was going in geosynchronous orbit in order to stay consistently over it’s service area
所以SSL需要把卫星横穿美国送到东海岸的佛州
so SSL needed to get the satellite all the way across the country to Florida.
甭管卫星去哪，都要先装进特制的运输箱内
No matter where a satellite is going, it gets packed up into one of these specialized shipping containers.
对于美国本土的运输，他们一般选择陆运
For travel to closer launch sites within the US they’ll often drive.
连上卡车，找像给虫这样(×)经验丰富的超限货物卡车司机来驾驶
They’ll put the container on a truck driven by trusted oversize vehicle drivers,
前面一个引导车检查路标
have a lead vehicle checking for obstructions,
后面跟着一辆车保证不出意外
a trailing vehicle watching to make sure nothing goes wrong,
还有个移动客舱，司机可以不耽误运输情况下轮流休息
and for longer drives a motorhome so drivers can swap out and rest while still moving.
如果发射场很远，比如海外的法属圭亚那或者哈萨克斯坦
If the launch site is far, such as the ones overseas in French Guyana, in Kazakstan,
甚至偶尔运到卡角，他们会用安东诺夫货机运送卫星
or even the further ones in the US such as Cape Canaveral they’ll fly the satellite over in an Antonov cargo plane.
卫星会在至少发射前一个月抵达发射场，因为还有很多准备工作要做
Satellites arrive to their launch sites at least a month before their launch as there’s plenty of last minute preparation to do.
他们要做额外的测试以保证运输过程中卫星没有损坏
They have to perform additional testing to make sure nothing was damaged in transport,
然后给卫星加燃料、放进火箭里
fuel it up, and mount it in the rocket.
一旦这些都完事，那有一段时间SSL就没什么事干了
Once that happens, though, there’s a period where there’s really nothing for SSL to do.
“当他们开始倒计时
“As they go through the process of the countdown
有一堆事情需要我们确认，确认可以发射
there are a number of places where we’re asked to confirm that we’re ready for launch,
然后他们发射了，从那时起我们就算暂时撒手不管了，直到星箭分离
then they launch us and at that point we can no longer monitor our satellite until we’re off the launch vehicle.
所以有大概半小时的时间我们在祈祷射火箭的人把活干明白
So for about a half hour we’re hoping that the launch vehicle guys are doing everything OK
而且通常他们都能做到”
and they usually are.”
Telstar 19V的客户选择太空叉来把卫星送到轨道
In the case of Telstar 19 Vantage, the customer entrusted SpaceX with the responsibility of getting their satellite to orbit,
所以在2018年7月22日东部时间1点50分
so on July 22nd, 2018 at 1:50 AM,
猎鹰九号载着SSL最新的产品从卡角前往太空
a Falcon 9 rocket lifted off from Cape Canaveral carrying SSL’s latest creation to space.
这颗卫星的发射还创造了一个新纪录
The launch of this satellite actually made the record books
它是当时上天的最重的商业卫星，重达15600磅(7076千克)
as it is the heaviest commercial communications satellite to ever be entered into service at 15,600 pounds.
在7月的那个凌晨，猎鹰九号在非洲东南部上空提升远地点
On that early morning in July, the Falcon 9 gained altitude as it flew south-east over Africa,
在发射32分钟40秒后，在莫桑比克上空358英里(576公里)
then 32 minutes and 40 seconds after launching, 358 miles above Mozambique,
Telstar 19V成功星箭分离
Telstar 19 Vantage was released from the rocket
缓缓离开二级火箭，开始了长达15年的太空生涯
and gently pushed forward in the first moments of it’s 15 year long orbit of earth.
但从这时开始，SSL的工作还未完成
At that point, the work’s not done for SSL, though.
他们的工作不止是制造卫星，还要让它入轨投入服务
Their job is not just to build the satellite but also to enter it into service in space.
当卫星分离后，SSL会搜寻它，与其建立联系
Once the satellite is deployed, SSL will look for its signal and establish communications.
“然后我们要和卫星‘对话’，给它发送指令
“and then we start talking to the satellite, we start commanding the satellite,
我们告诉卫星让它干啥，让它在发射后进入一个安全位置
we tell the satellite what we want it to do, we start to get the satellite into a safe position after launch,
我们会展开太阳帆板从而让它有电，然后启动其他所有东西
we’ll deploy solar arrays so we can start generating power, we’ll start to activate everything on the satellite
将它送入安全的条件下，这样我们地面人员就能歇会了”
and we’ll put the satellite in the safe condition so that the crew can start to get some rest.”
接下来十天里卫星会启动几次发动机
Over the next ten days there’s a process of firing the satellite’s engines
把轨道从星箭分离的350英里(563公里)
to raise it from the altitude of 350 miles where it was deployed
提升到最终工作轨道22000英里(约35800公里)
to 22,000 miles where it will stay for its service life.
接下来是两到四周的测试，来保证一切在发射后都正常运行
There’s then another two to four weeks of testing to make sure everything survived launch,
最后，在几年的辛劳后，该把卫星交接给客户TeleSat了
and then, finally, after years of work, it’s time to hand over the satellite to Telesat, the customer,
他们终于可以让卫星上线，正式开始商业运营了
so they can put it online and start operating it commercially.
从此，花费了多年的功夫后，卫星终于开始干活了
At that point, after years of work the satellite can finally itself be put to work.
字幕翻译给虫，欢迎点赞投币收藏分享转发评论关注充电~
在制作这个视频中我学到关于卫星的最有意思的东西是
One of the aspects of how satellites work that I found most interesting to learn about when I filmed this video
轨道的原理
was on how orbits work.
让物体在天上同步地球自转背后的科学太有趣了
The science of how you can make an object orbit at such a consistent speed
that it will stay still over one particular area of earth is fascinating
如果你想学习这些，Brilliant在经典力学的课程里都有教
and if you want to learn all about how that works, Brilliant teaches you exactly that in their classical mechanics course.
当然不止有轨道力学，该课程提供了物理里很大范围的内容
Of course there’s more than just orbits, this course provides a great overview of physics,
而通过Brilliant，你不止能学到知识，还能深刻理解这些概念
and with Brilliant, you’ll actually understand the concepts rather than just learning them.
他们专门教会你概念背后直觉上的定律，让你知其所以然
They specialize in teaching the intuitive principles behind concepts so that you learn the why.
他们还有很多其他不错的课程，比如天文学、逻辑学、引力物理学
They also have plenty of other fascinating courses on topics like astronomy, logic, and gravitational physics
——教你星星的轨道原理的~
—a course that teaches how planetary orbits work.
总之，Brilliant是个很不错的学习的网站
All in all, Brilliant is a great place to learn
更好的是，你可以通过下方链接试听Brilliant的课程
and best of all, you can try Brilliant classes for free by signing up at brilliant.org/Wendover
如果你决定成为会员，前200人还可以得到8折优惠~
and then, if you decide to upgrade to their premium account, the first 200 to do so at that link will get 20% off.